[ phone ringing ]
Dr. Cotter .
He 's gonna die . She 's gonna die . Mom 's gonna die .
I 'm gonna die . Everybody dies .
I don 't wanna - - I 'm gonna - -
I haven 't been able to get him to talk ...
respond to me , nothing .
[ muttering continues ]
Just this .
Yeah . I got it .
Thanks , Dan .
She 's gonna die . Mom 's gonna die . I 'm gonna die . Everyone dies .
Nobody matters . She doesn 't matter . He doesn 't matter . Mom doesn 't matter .
I don 't matter . Nothing ever matters . I don 't matter .
I don 't matter . He 's gonna die . She 's gonna die .
He 's gonna die . I 'm gonna die . Everyone dies .
Nobody matters . She doesn 't matter . He doesn 't matter .
Everyone dies . I 'm gonna die . Nobody matters .
She doesn 't matter . He doesn 't matter .
Mom doesn 't matter . Nothing ever matters . I don 't matter .
I 'm gonna - - I 'm gonna - - I 'm gonna - - I 'm gonna - -
She 's gonna - - She 's gonna - - Everyone - - I 'm gonna - -
I don 't matter . I 'm gonna - - I 'm gonna - -
[ whimpering ]
Hi , Carl .
What 's going on today ?
I 'm dying .
No .
I don 't think so .
I think you 're having another manic episode .
Don 't - -
Don 't you tell me .
You don 't know .
I feel it all around me , squeezing .
[ whimpering continues ]
I 'm scared .
Carl , I know that what you 're experiencing feels real ,
but it can 't hurt you .
[ whimpering ]
I promise .
He 's gonna die . She 's gonna die . Mom 's gonna die . I 'm gonna die .
Everyone dies . Nobody matters . She doesn 't matter .
Hey , Wanda .
I 'm gonna put Carl Renken into observation for a few days . He 's harmless .
Just make sure someone checks on him every couple hours .
- You got it . - Thanks .
Hey , Dr. Desai was looking for you .
Thank you .
[ siren wailing ]
[ patient ] No ! No ! Please !
Please ! You don 't understand ! I can 't go in there ! No !
[ screaming ] No ! No ! Please !
No !
[ knocking ]
Come in .
Hey , did you send a patient named , uh ,
Sarah Marquet over to residency yesterday ?
Yes . She has a history with drug abuse and mania ,
and she 's been in and out of our unit a few times .
[ sighs ] Rose , she has no insurance .
Okay , but she needs treatment .
The board is down my throat about paying out of pocket
for another bed in the residency program .
The board should try giving a shit about the point of our job here once in a while .
[ sighs ]
I 'm not questioning your judgment .
I just need you to come to me first so I can get ahead of it next time .
- All right ? - Yes .
Okay . I 'm sorry .
Hey , you haven 't been here since the late shift last night , have you ?
[ distant hospital intercom chatter ]
[ phone ringing ]
[ door opens ]
[ Rose ] Dr. Cotter .
Laura Weaver , 26 . She 's a grad student .
Police were called on her for public disturbance .
- EMS brought her in . - Got any psych history ?
Nothing on file , but the police sent over a report
for a different incident she was involved in last week .
And what was that one about ?
A professor at her school bludgeoned himself to death with a hammer .
She was interviewed as the only witness .
A hammer ?
Hi .
Laura ?
[ gasps ]
My name is Dr. Cotter . I 'm a therapist .
Do you wanna sit down ?
- [ gasps ] - Okay .
I know you 're nervous .
That 's okay .
I just wanna have a chat .
I promise this is a safe place .
Not for me .
Why do you say that ?
[ breathes shakily ]
Come on . Let 's sit .
Please .
[ recording device beeps ]
Okay . I 'm gonna ask you a couple of questions
that might sound stupid .
What day of the week is it ?
Thursday .
And the month ?
October . I 'm not crazy .
- Nobody 's saying that . - But I need you to understand .
I 'm a PhD candidate . I 'm not some lunatic . Okay ?
Let 's just take a breath , and you can just tell me what 's going on .
[ breathing shakily ]
I 'm seeing something .
Something no one else can see except for me . [ inhales sharply ]
I know how insane that sounds . I do .
But it 's - - This thing , I can 't explain it .
What is it you 're seeing ?
It looks like people ,
but it 's - - it 's not a person .
I 'm not sure I understand .
It looks like people . It looks like different people .
Sometimes it pretends to be someone that I know .
Sometimes it 's a random stranger . Sometimes - -
Sometimes it looks like my grandfather
who died in front of me when I was seven .
But it 's all the same thing . It - -
It 's - - It 's like - -
It 's - - It 's like it wears people 's faces like - - like masks .
[ softly ] Okay .
Do you see it right now , here ?
What happens when you do see it ?
It 's smiling at me .
But not a friendly smile .
It 's the worst smile I 've ever seen in my life .
And whenever I see it , I just get this god-awful feeling
like something really terrible is gonna happen .
I 've never felt scared like I do when I see it .
Laura , have you or anyone else in your family
ever experienced hallucinations ?
It 's not a hallucination , no . It 's real .
You don 't get it . It does things to me .
It causes shit to happen around me .
It 's taken over my whole life and my mind and ...
it tells me things .
It told me that to - - today - - Today 's the - -
Today 's the day that I 'm - - I 'm gonna - -
Okay . That 's okay .
That 's okay .
I know that what you 're experiencing feels incredibly real .
Sometimes , when we get emotionally overwhelmed ,
or experience an intense trauma , our minds tend to - -
You 're not listening to me .
Oh , my God .
I 'm gonna fucking die , and no one will listen to me .
Okay . Laura , it 's okay .
[ crying ] Oh , God .
Hey , it 's okay . Laura .
Hey , c-can you look at me , please ?
[ whispers ] It 's okay .
Look at me .
I - -
[ screaming ]
Oh , my God . No !
No ! It 's here !
- Please ! - Laura . It 's okay .
- It 's just us . - Get away ! Please !
- There 's nobody else here . - No !
[ screaming ]
No !
[ choking , gasping ]
Oh , my God .
I - - I have a patient emergency in eval 2 . I need staff here now .
Hurry .
[ breathing heavily ]
Laura ?
[ gasping ]
[ no audible dialogue ]
[ detective ] Had Ms. Weaver ever been a patient here before ?
[ Rose ] No .
Would you say she was typical of the patients you see here ?
This is an emergency psychiatric unit .
Typical is not really a thing here .
Right . But she was a head case , yeah ?
I 'm sorry , a head case ?
I think we 're just trying to get your opinion of her mental state .
She could 've been suffering from ... acute post-trauma psychosis .
[ inhales sharply ] She was having paranoid delusions .
What kind of delusions ?
She was convinced that some ... sort of evil presence was haunting her .
Yikes .
It 's just , we 're gonna have to contact Ms. Weaver 's family
and attempt to explain what happened .
So we 're looking for anything that might make some sense of all this .
If there 's anything else you can tell us , that - - that might help .
Uh , before she died ...
she was ... smiling .
Yeah , she sounds fucking crazy to me .
[ meows ]
[ purring ]
[ sighs ]
[ sighs , sniffles ]
[ breathes shakily ]
[ sighs ]
[ exhales ]
[ gulps ]
- [ person ] Rose . - [ gasps ]
Whoa .
My bad . Did I scare you ?
I didn 't hear you come in . Shit .
- Hi . - Hi . [ chuckles ]
Hi .
What 's up ?
Nothing . Sorry .
Something 's wrong .
A patient died today .
My patient .
Oh .
Hey , come here .
I 'm sorry .
It happened right in front of me .
It was awful .
I 'm so sorry . What can I do ?
This is a nice start .
Maybe we should bail on dinner tonight .
[ chuckles ] We can 't .
Holly hired a sitter ,
and it 's just gonna be a bigger headache if we don 't go .
No way . Holly turning into a headache ?
[ chuckles ]
Hey .
[ sighs ]
[ Holly 's voice muffled ] I 'm sorry , you wanna talk about being tired ?
Now that Jackson 's in the first grade , I 'm literally up at 6 : 00 a.m. every day
to make him breakfast and pack him lunch .
God knows what kind of non organic garbage that cafeteria is even serving .
[ clear voice ] Then I have to drive him to school ,
barely have any time to run my own errands .
Like , I haven 't been to Pilates in weeks .
- Okay , my body is so fucked . - Not true .
I have to go back to school , pick him up ,
then I have to take him to either soccer practice ,
swim lessons , karate , theater - -
Oh , and he just started taking Spanish .
[ chuckles ] I mean , my weekdays are literally impossible .
Mmm . You are coming Saturday , right ?
What ?
Uh , sorry , what 's Saturday ?
- I 'm sorry , is that a joke ? - Wow .
- Rose , Jackson 's seventh birthday party . - Wow .
- I 've told you , like , five times . - [ sighs ]
I can 't . I have work .
What do you mean work ? It 's Saturday .
I work Saturday .
See , this is exactly why you have to get out of that gross hospital
- and into a private practice ... - Gross ?
- It is not gross . - ... working normal-people hours .
Rose , there have to be plenty of crazies out there
who will actually pay you for your time .
Thank you so much for your input , Greg .
That 's very sweet .
I 'm just saying , why become a doctor
if you can 't get disgustingly rich ? [ chuckles ]
[ partner ] You 're kidding , right ?
Rose loves being a doctor . She 'd do it for free .
[ chuckles ] What ...
Well , on the subject of wasted earning potentials ,
- we could always sell the fucking house . - Can we not right now ?
I don 't understand you . It 's just sitting there .
We grew up in that house .
Rose , it 's a total teardown . Why not just get the money for the land ?
Can you guys just shut the fuck up ?
Wow .
Thank you .
- Thank you so much . - Sure .
I 've been looking forward to this .
[ meows ]
[ typing on keypad ]
[ alarm beeps ]
[ Rose sighs ]
You okay ?
Yeah .
[ cat meows ]
[ purring ]
[ distant siren wailing ]
Morning , Doc .
Morning .
Hey . Yesterday , that patient , Laura Weaver - -
The police had sent a report bout a different incident
that she was involved in .
- Can you get that forwarded to me ? - You got it , Doc .
Also , I was supposed to have a session with Jane Park .
Oh , yeah . She pulled out a bunch of her hair overnight
and swallowed it all .
They took her down to medicine to have her stomach pumped .
- Shit . - [ detective clears throat ]
Uh , Rose .
- What - - What are you - - - I was on a - - I was on a call nearby ,
and I just thought I would - -
Um - -
We didn 't really get to talk yesterday , other than the whole - - whole thing .
And I just wanted you to know that when the call came in ,
I had no idea it was gonna be you .
So , I 'm sorry if that was weird .
It 's your job . I get it .
How you been ?
Joel , why are you here ?
Like I said , I was on a call nearby , and I just - -
I thought I would ...
come check on you .
After everything that happened yesterday , that 's - - that 's not an easy thing .
Okay . I appreciate it , but I don 't need you to check on me .
Right .
No , yeah , I mean - - Sorry .
I have to get back to work .
- Yeah . - See you around .
You do know she 's engaged , right ?
Yeah .
I 'm single .
[ cell phone ringing ]
[ sighs ]
- [ Rose ] Hello . - [ Holly ] Hi .
Um , look , I just wanted to say sorry about last night , okay ?
I shouldn 't have kept going at you like that .
Uh , no , I - -
I should apologize .
I 've been just dealing with some stuff .
I wasn 't being very good company .
Okay . If you can 't make it to your nephew 's party tomorrow ,
you could at least get him a present .
If you need an idea , he 's really into electric model trains .
[ Rose ] Uh-huh .
You sound weird . Are you okay ?
Yeah , no , I 'm fine . [ chuckles ]
Hey , Carl .
How you feeling today ?
Carl .
Carl ?
She 's gonna die . I 'm gonna die .
- Everybody dies . - Carl , look at me .
You 're going to die .
You 're going to die . You 're going to die .
- You 're going to die . - Help !
Help ! This patient is 5150 !
- He needs to be restrained ! - Go , go , go !
[ screaming ] No ! No !
No !
No ! No ! No ! No !
No ! No !
No !
[ pen clicks ]
He was aggressive .
Acting psychotic .
Carl Renken has been in and out of here a dozen times
and has never exhibited behavior even remotely aggressive .
- Do you think I 'm making it up ? - Of course not .
But yesterday , a patient in your care
killed herself brutally in front of you .
Is it possible , when you presumed
that Carl Renken was a danger to himself ,
that that 's what your mind was reacting to ?
[ exhales ]
I suppose I could 've misinterpreted the situation and overreacted .
Okay .
So , here 's what 's gonna happen .
You 're gonna take a paid week off .
Morgan , that 's really not necessary .
You 've been working 80-hour weeks for months .
I 'm concerned that you haven 't been sleeping .
We can 't help these patients unless we have our own mental health in check .
And it 's in the unit 's best interest
if you just take a week and clear your head .
Just do what you gotta do and come back focused , okay ?
[ siren blaring ]
[ breathing heavily ]
[ exhaling ]
[ no audible dialogue ]
[ cell phone chimes ]
[ inhales deeply ]
- [ intruder alarm wailing ] - [ shrieks ]
Fuck !
[ Rose groans ]
[ alarm continues wailing ]
- [ control panel beeps ] - [ alarm stops ]
[ breathes heavily ]
[ wind whistling ]
- [ phone ringing ] - [ gasps ]
- [ breathing shakily ] Hello ? - This is First Line Security .
May I have your name and the passcode ?
Uh , Rose Cotter .
Um , " Acapulco . "
Ma 'am , we 've detected a door alarm .
Yeah , uh , the - - the back door of my house is open .
Are you alone in the house , ma 'am ?
Yes .
Are you sure ?
What ?
Are you sure you haven 't let something inside , Rose ?
Look behind you .
[ breathing shakily ]
- [ phone ringing ] - [ gasps ]
[ ringing continues ]
Shit .
Hello ?
This is First Line Security .
May I have your name and the passcode ?
[ police radio chatter ]
[ door closes ]
We did a full sweep inside and out . It 's all clear .
Um , what about the back door ?
Is it possible it wasn 't fully latched last time it was closed ?
I - - I don 't know . Maybe .
Hey , I wouldn 't worry about it .
These false alarms happen all the time .
If anything else comes up , you can give us a call .
Okay .
[ officer ] Evening , sir .
Um , evening .
What happened ?
Mustache ?
Mustache .
So , is there a reason you set the alarm ?
Uh - -
I literally don 't remember doing it .
I must have just , like , set it by accident or something .
By accident ?
Sorry . Sorry .
My head has just been in this , like , foggy , creepy , spacey place all day .
And there was this weird incident at work and then - -
And then my boss is making me take a - -
[ exhales ]
Sorry . [ chuckles ]
- Everything is okay . - Are you sure ?
No , no , I 'm fine . I was just venting .
Okay .
Can you see if you can find Mustache ?
I haven 't seen him anywhere at all .
Yeah .
Rose , did you break another glass ?
Mustache ?
[ Rose hissing ]
Come on , kitty .
Please . Please .
Mustache .
[ gasping ]
[ Laura on recording ] It looks like people . It looks like different people .
Sometimes it pretends to be someone that I know .
Sometimes it 's a random stranger . Sometimes - -
Sometimes it looks like my grandfather
who died in front of me when I was seven .
- But it 's all the same thing . It - - - [ audio fast forwards ]
It 's smiling at me , but not a friendly smile .
It 's the worst smile I 've ever seen in my life .
And whenever I see it , I just get this god-awful feeling
like something really terrible is gonna happen .
[ audio fast forwards ]
Oh , my God ! No ! No !
No ! It 's here ! Please !
Get away ! Please ! No !
[ screaming ]
[ Rose ] I - - I have a patient emergency in eval 2 .
I need staff here now . Hurry .
Laura ?
[ whispering ]
[ whispers ] Rose .
[ audio pauses ]
- [ audio rewinds ] - [ volume increases ]
[ Rose ] Laura ?
- Rose ! - [ screams ]
[ shouting ]
- Rose ? - [ screams ]
Whoa ! Oh , my God ! Rose ! Rose ! Whoa , whoa !
What the fuck ? Rose , put the knife down !
[ gasping , crying ]
Rose !
[ Rose ] Hi .
Rose ?
This is a surprise .
[ Rose ] It wasn 't so much the blood .
It was , um ...
her face .
The look that she had .
How did it make you feel ?
Uh - -
Terrified , obviously .
Um - -
Vulnerable .
Guilty .
Guilty ?
Well , she was my patient .
She was a disturbed young woman you only met for ten minutes .
[ chuckles ] Yeah . I just - -
I just feel like I 've gotten stuck on it .
I can 't , you know , get it out of my head .
Have you considered the reason you feel stuck
could actually be more about your mother 's suicide ?
Do you still blame yourself ?
That - -
I 'm really not trying to relitigate
that part of my life right now . So ...
What would you like to talk about ?
I was hoping that I could get a script for Risperdal .
Ever since that ...
patient , I 've been , um ...
seeing things
and hearing things .
I 'm sure it 's just a symptom of post-trauma .
Let 's avoid any self-diagnosis .
What is it you 've been seeing and hearing ?
Echoes of what happened with my patient .
You know , just fleeting moments
of stress-induced hallucinations .
But when they 're happening , they feel so ...
corporeal and unsettling .
Rose , from where I 'm sitting , you don 't seem delusional or disordered to me .
And certainly not psychotic .
It 's my impression this experience with your patient
triggered old anxieties compounded with too much stress , not enough sleep .
You have wounds that have never fully healed .
It is possible they never will completely . That 's the nature of trauma .
But you can learn to get control over it .
Have you been continuing to see patients
while you 've been coping with all this ?
- No . I 'm just taking a short hiatus . - Good .
If you want my advice ,
use this time to do something different .
Anything that will take your mind off
the triggers that are causing you stress .
I also think it would be helpful
if we resumed our regular sessions again .
Sure .
And what about the Risperdal ? Just - - You know .
Let 's talk again next week before we consider any medication .
In the meantime , you can always call me .
Sure .
- [ doorbell rings ] - I asked you for a white wine spritzer .
Jesus .
- Oh , my God . You made it . - Hi . Surprise .
- Come on in . Come on in . - Oh .
I thought you had to work ?
- Oh , I decided to take the afternoon ... - I 'll take that .
Hey , Greg . What are you doing ?
- I told you not to take those out yet . - Mmm , mmm .
Geez .
Uh , ladies , I have to go corral my dipshit husband .
Would one of you please show my sister to the adult refreshments ?
Sure . We have a stash in the kitchen . Come on .
Wait . You 're that therapist , right ?
Yes , I - - I am .
Oh ! Fantastic . Can I ask for advice ?
♪ Happy birthday to you ♪
♪ Happy birthday ... ♪
[ singing sustains , distorts , fades ]
[ no audible dialogue ]
So cool .
Gracias , Harper . Gracias , Harper 's mom .
[ guests chattering , chuckling ]
Ooh , that one 's from Aunt Rose .
[ child ] Open it !
[ child 2 ] Rip it open !
What 'd you get , sweetheart ?
- [ guests clamoring ] - [ children screaming ]
No . No .
- Oh , my God . - No , no . Mustache .
What the hell is wrong with you ?
This can 't be happening .
No . No , no . No , I promise you , this wasn 't me .
It wasn 't . It wasn 't me , I swear .
You have to - - You guys have to believe me , please .
Somebody please fucking believe me .
[ gasps ]
What the fuck are you ? Leave me the fuck alone !
You see her . You have to see her .
Please , Holly , tell me that you see somebody .
Please .
[ screams ]
[ guests exclaiming ]
- [ guest ] Oh , my God . - [ guest 2 ] Oh , God .
[ gasping ]
[ children crying ]
[ screaming ]
- [ knocks ] - Hey , Rose .
Fuck .
I heard you were brought into the ER .
I wanted to come check on you . How 're you doing ?
Fine .
It was just an accident . Thank you .
Yeah . They - - They said that you had had a anxiety attack . [ sighs ]
Rose , I 'll be honest with you , I 'm - - I 'm concerned .
And I - - I mean this as your friend ,
but I really think you should speak to someone .
Are you seeing anybody professionally right now ?
[ no audible dialogue ]
[ Dr. Desai ] Rose , are you listening ?
Wait .
I need to tell you something ,
and I need you to know that I 'm not crazy , okay ?
Okay .
Um - -
Something is happening to me .
And it 's gonna be really hard for you to believe .
Maybe we should just go inside .
No , wait . Just listen to me ! Sorry . Sorry .
I 'm really sorry .
Okay , um - -
Something is threatening me .
Some kind of a evil spirit , or energy .
I - - I don 't really know what it is , but - -
But I think that it - - it killed my patient .
Because she described experiencing the same thing before she died .
And now it 's somehow attached itself to me .
And ...
I 'm just really scared
that something bad is going to happen .
I really need you to say something .
What do you want me to say ?
I want you to believe me .
Rose , you 're talking about a fucking ghost .
No , no , no . It 's not - -
It 's not a ghost .
It 's something else .
Okay .
I 'm sorry .
I can 't .
I cannot fucking do this right now .
No . Trevor .
Whoa , wait . No , no , no . Don 't walk away .
I need you - - You 're not listening to what I am saying .
Okay , Rose .
What the fuck am I supposed to say to respond to this right now ?
Do you hear yourself ? I mean , Jesus Christ . You sound crazy .
I am not crazy !
[ whispers ] Sorry . Sorry .
But it 's genetic , isn 't it ?
What ?
Mental illness .
You can inherit it from a parent .
I looked it up .
Why would you look that up ?
Because ...
I wanted to know what I was potentially hitching my entire life to .
Is that so fucking unfair ?
I 'm going in the house .
No , no , no . Please , Trevor . I 'm in danger !
Rose .
- Did you kill Mustache ? - N - - No !
No ! That was not - - That was not me .
Then tell me , what happened to him ?
It was the thing .
Trevor , please .
Please . Please .
- [ voice ] Rose . - [ gasps ]
[ voice whispers ] Come here .
Rose .
[ Rose crying ]
[ voice ] Baby ...
Please . Help me .
- Mommy made a mistake . - [ Rose ] No , no , no .
[ whimpering ]
No , no , no .
- [ voice shouts ] Rose ! - [ horn honks ]
[ driver ] Look where you 're going !
- Are you crazy ? - Sorry . I 'm sorry .
[ tires squeal ]
[ doorbell rings ]
[ breathing heavily ]
Mrs. Muñoz ?
[ Mrs. Muñoz ] At first , I noticed small changes in him .
Then it all happened so fast .
He was on edge .
Paranoid .
He would wake up in the middle of the night , screaming .
I 'd never heard him scream before .
Then he just stopped sleeping altogether .
I would catch him having these conversations with himself .
He was seeing things .
Doing strange things that he didn 't even seem to remember .
Then one morning he was gone .
That night , the police called and told me he was dead .
They asked me to identify his body .
[ crying ] His face .
[ sniffles ] Twenty-five years of marriage ,
and that 's what I have left to remember him .
I 'm so sorry .
[ sniffles ]
[ sobbing ]
Did Gabriel ever describe the things that he was seeing ?
I 'll show you .
I should take it all down ,
but I can 't stand being in here .
This is what Gabriel said he saw .
He kept saying it was trying to get inside of him .
That is Gabriel 's brother .
He died in an accident 20 years ago .
Gabriel never got over it .
[ Rose ] How long had this been going on ?
Ever since he got back
from that damn conference he would go to every year .
It was because he saw that awful woman kill herself .
But no one reports on that .
He watched someone die by suicide ?
Yes .
I assumed you knew this .
What was her name ?
I don 't remember . I 'd have to find it .
Um - -
Did - - Did he ever , um ...
say why all of this was happening ?
Did he find any explanation in all of this ?
What kind of reporter are you ?
Mrs. Muñoz , your husband was not insane .
The things that he was seeing , they 're real . I 've seen them .
What are you , a fucking nutcase ?
- What ? - Some kind of morbid fanatic ?
How fucking dare you ?
No , please . Please .
What happened to your husband is happening to me .
Out of my house . I want you out of my house , now .
Just please give me the name . Please , just give me the name !
Get the fuck out of my house !
[ engine starts ]
Oh , fuck . Shit .
[ Joel ] Yeah ?
Hey .
Come on in .
Finally got rid of that ugly yellow couch .
Uh-huh .
So , uh , what 's up ?
I assume you 're not here to catch up
considering the cold shoulder the other day .
- I need a favor . - [ chuckles ]
I need you to not ask any questions about it .
Terrific . Yeah , let 's hear that .
Uh , so , nine days ago ,
a man named Gabriel Muñoz killed himself .
I need to know if he had been involved in any other recent police reports .
Can you find that out ? Here , for me .
Come on . Are you serious ?
This is my one day off . Go to the station .
Joel , please ?
[ sighs ]
[ exhales ]
Fine .
Goddamn it .
[ groans ]
All right , what was his name again ?
Gabriel Muñoz .
All right . I see the report on his death .
Yeah . There 's another incident report here
from a week earlier , from a precinct upstate .
- What was it for ? - He gave a witness statement .
He was staying at a hotel where a woman committed suicide .
Okay , um - - And what was her name ? The woman ?
Um ,
Angela Powell .
She 's a real estate agent .
What is this ?
[ gasps ]
- Fuck . - What ? What is it ?
It 's a picture from the scene .
- Let me see it . - No .
- Let me see it . - No , no .
Look , you don 't wanna see this . This is , like , evidence .
Or , just , you know , have at it .
[ gasps ]
Holy shit .
[ Joel sighs ]
Told you it was gross .
Okay , um - -
Okay , uh , I need you to do the same search again ,
but this time on her .
The woman , Angela .
Can you please tell me what this is all about ?
Joel , you said you weren 't gonna ask me any questions .
No . You said I wouldn 't ask you any questions .
Joel , I need your help .
Okay ?
Please ?
- [ sighs ] - [ typing ]
Hmm .
There was a previous report
filed four days before her death .
That 's a weird coincidence .
She was also interviewed about a suicide .
What is this ? Is that a video file ?
It 's , um , security camera footage .
- Put it - - Put it on . - Just - - It 's - - It 's loading .
What the fuck is this ?
[ groans ]
You know , my day was going just fine .
- Can you rewind it ? - Really ?
Rewind it , Joel .
Okay , stop .
[ Joel ] Is he smiling ?
Rose , who are these people ?
I have to go .
Where are you going ?
Rose , where are you going ? What is going on here ?
I 'm so confused right now .
Can you do me one more favor ?
Do you have a printer ?
[ lock clicks ]
Trevor . Trevor , you here ?
Hey .
Hi , Rose .
What is this ? What is she doing here ?
I wanted to see how you were doing .
I was talking to my fiancé .
I called her .
Why ?
Because you 've been acting completely unhinged .
I - - I don 't - -
And I - - I didn 't know what else to do .
[ Rose ] Are you fucking kidding me ?
I came to you , the person I 'm supposed to trust most in the world ,
and I - - I confided that I was scared to death .
That I needed you .
And you didn 't listen to a word I was saying .
No . Why do you think I even called her ?
All I 'm trying to do here is help you .
No ! All you 're trying to do is make it so you don 't have to deal with it .
You 're fine as long as everything is easy and agreeable ,
but God forbid anything become real ,
or even a tiny bit difficult .
And - - And you just - -
You think about how it 's gonna fuck up your whole little perfect life plan .
- Are you serious right now ? - Yeah .
If that 's how you feel , then why are we even together ?
Maybe I just don 't know .
Why don 't we all just take a breath - -
Why don 't you just fucking make yourself at home !
Rose , are you actually leaving right now ?
[ door slams ]
[ doorbell rings ]
- Greg . - Rose , what are you doing here ?
- Is Holly here ? I need to talk to her . - I don 't think that 's a good idea .
Greg , let me talk to my fucking sister . Holly !
You 're gonna come and talk to me like that ?
Holly , can I talk to you , just for one sec ?
- No , I don 't think - - - Can I please talk to you ?
I don 't think this is a good idea . Honestly .
- Yeah , it 's fine . It 's fine . - Holly .
- Just go the fuck inside . - I don 't - - All right . Fine .
[ whispers ] Jesus .
[ whispering ] Okay , okay , okay .
How are you ?
My eyes are open now .
I have been cursed .
Okay , uh - -
Or somehow wrapped up in a curse .
I - - I got it from my patient .
She was cursed , and then when she died , she - - she transferred it to me .
And now I 'm being threatened by this - - this entity .
- By an entity ? - No , no .
It - - It 's what killed Mustache .
It was at the party yesterday , but you couldn 't see it .
Nobody else can see it , except for me .
Jesus Christ .
No , look , Holly ,
I know it 's so hard to believe ,
and it was difficult for me to believe it at first either .
But look - - look at this . Look .
Oh , my God . Rose . Why the fuck do you have that ?
Because this has happened to other people .
- And they 're all dead . - Rose .
And I - - Holly , I 'm gonna be next !
Rose , curses are not real .
Okay ? You are having some sort of a - -
A breakdown .
What ? No , no . Holly .
You 're not hearing me .
- You are not hearing me . - Rose .
This is exactly what happened to Mom .
You sound just like her .
How the fuck would you know that ?
I 'm sorry , what ?
You were never around when Mom got bad .
Where the fuck were you when she died ?
You have no idea what you 're talking about .
Okay ? Because I was older , I got the worst of Mom 's insanity .
I had to fucking leave the house .
That was the only way I - - I could survive .
And I 'm - - I 'm sorry
that I left you alone and that you had to be the one to find her .
I know that that fucked you up , and - -
And I know that that 's not fair .
I wish I could do something about it ,
but , Rose , I have tried so hard to move on with my life ,
to leave all of that shit behind me , okay ?
You , it 's like you can 't accept the fact
that Mom lost her mind and fucking killed herself .
And you let it define your entire life ,
and you punish me because I don 't want to .
Well , I 'm sorry that I 'm actually trying to help people
instead of being some fucking stay-at-home PTA housewife ,
who lives in her own self-centered , smug little bubble !
- Okay . - I don 't know why I said that .
You know what , I 'm - - I 'm not doing this . I 'm not doing this with you .
You 've completely traumatized Jackson , okay ?
I can 't have you around when you 're like this .
[ door slams ]
Fuck .
[ exhales ]
- [ knocking ] - [ gasps ] Holly ?
[ screaming ]
[ shouting ]
Fuck ! Fuck !
[ shouting continues ]
Fuck !
Motherfucker !
[ cell phone ringing ]
Joel ?
Why didn 't you tell me about your patient 's connection to the others ?
- Wha - - - After you left , I kept digging .
These cases ?
This same pattern . It goes back further .
So far , I 've found 20 cases involving 19 suicide victims
with a direct line linking them all together .
And the things these people are doing to themselves , Rose .
Holy shit .
Wait , you said , um , 20 cases , but only 19 suicides .
One of the cases mixes up the pattern .
Some accountant , Robert Talley .
His business partner commits suicide right in front of him ,
and four days later , Talley goes
and fucking murders a woman he 's never met before ,
completely out of the blue .
But get this , a week later ,
the key eyewitness to the murder
also commits suicide .
Pattern resumes .
- So , he 's alive ? - Yeah .
He 's sitting in holding in Altoona .
Joel , I gotta talk to him .
I 'm gonna need you to say something .
Yeah , I - - I will .
Just - - Just - -
[ sighs ]
Give me a second . I mean , Jesus - -
I thought you were gonna say this was some kind of , like ,
crazy suicide cult , or blackmail scheme .
- I mean , this ? This is - - This ? This is - - - Hey , Joel .
Okay .
Let 's just put aside the possibility
that some sort of evil , extraordinary force could even exist .
What you 're saying is that this thing is jumping around
from person to person ,
and it is causing them to kill themselves ?
Okay , but maybe it 's not suicide .
What do you mean ?
Okay . So , my patient , she was terrified ,
but she was not suicidal .
And then at - - at the end , everything about her changed .
It was like the person I had been talking to was gone .
And something else had taken over .
[ stammering ] So , it 's kind of like the guy ...
- Yes . - ... on the security camera footage ?
[ Rose ] Yes . Yes . Exactly like that .
Oh , my God . What the fuck ?
In the cases that you found , um ...
how long was it between each victim 's death ?
None of them survived longer than a week .
Some of them didn 't even make it past four days .
[ exhales ]
Today was my fourth day .
Hey .
Whatever happened to those people ,
it 's not gonna happen to you .
I promise .
[ train horn blows ]
[ guard on PA ] Transfer guard to gate three .
Transfer guard to gate three .
[ Joel ] Thank you .
[ guard 2 ] Give them a buzz through .
- They 're clear . - [ door buzzes , opens ]
[ Joel ] I owe you one for this , Doug .
[ chuckles ] You 're just lucky that he fired every lawyer he was assigned .
You do know what this guy did , right ?
Well , Dr. Cotter 's building a psychological profile
on a similar case for us .
Oh . Well , Talley 's a whole box of fruit loops .
So , good luck .
Look , you only got ten minutes with him , okay ?
It 's the best I could do without a court order .
Well , I appreciate it .
[ door buzzes ]
[ radio chatter ]
- [ door closes ] - [ lock clicks ]
Mr. Talley , my name is Dr. Rose Cotter ,
and , um , I was hoping you 'd be willing to answer some questions about - -
I 'm done answering questions . I confessed .
I actually don 't care about what you were accused of .
What I need to know is what you experienced
in the days leading up to it .
I have a patient ,
a young woman .
Four days ago ,
a man killed himself right in front of her .
And ever since then , she has been seeing something .
[ sighs ]
Something that pretends to be other people .
The man that she saw kill himself ,
he claimed that he was seeing the exact same thing .
What the fuck do you want from me , huh ?
- What is it ? - I don 't know .
I don 't know .
Why is it that everybody else
who 's seen it is dead and you 're alive ?
Why ? Please .
Mr. Talley , you can help her . Okay ?
Please .
[ train rumbling ]
Make the cop leave .
Not gonna happen , pal .
Make him leave , and I 'll tell you what I know .
Joel , please .
I 'll be outside , all right ?
[ knocks ]
- [ door closes ] - [ lock clicks ]
I tried to research anything and everything I could about this thing .
There 's been other chains in the past .
Found one that was in Brazil a few years ago .
A man there escaped that chain
by killing his neighbor and passing it to his neighbor 's wife .
Your patient is going to die
unless she kills someone .
That 's the only way you can get rid of it .
The only way .
She has to make sure there 's a witness for it to pass to ,
' cause this thing needs trauma to spread .
That 's what gives it power . Trauma .
Your patient has to make it count .
Tell her to use some kind of weapon .
Make the biggest mess she can - -
I can 't kill someone ! [ gasps ]
You ?
[ gasps ] You have it ?
No , no , no . Why the fuck did you come here ?
You 're not giving it back to me .
- Get out of here ! - I 'm sorry .
Get out of here !
Get her away from me !
[ screams ]
Hey .
Hey ! Wait .
- What happened in there ? - Nothing .
What 'd he say ?
Nothing .
Nothing ?
He 's out of his fucking mind , Joel .
[ lock clicks ]
[ sighs ]
[ cell phone ringing ]
[ ringing stops ]
[ cell phone chimes ]
Ah , fuck .
[ sighs ]
[ doorbell rings ]
What are you doing here ?
I apologize if you felt ambushed yesterday .
That was the wrong approach .
- I 'm sorry . - Yeah .
- I think you should go . - Rose .
We both know I have a responsibility to notify the authorities
if you 're a danger to yourself or others .
I need you to help convince me you 're not a danger .
Trevor mentioned there had been talk of ghosts .
I never used the word " ghosts . "
Evil beings , then . Paranormal .
I admitted to him that I was seeing things ,
the same thing that I told you .
That 's not happening anymore . Okay ?
It was stress and lack of sleep .
I confided in him , and that was obviously a mistake .
But that 's it .
Okay ? Are we good ?
How are you feeling today ?
[ scoffs ]
Let me think , um - -
I 'm pretty sure my fiancé thinks I 'm crazy .
My sister has just totally shut me out .
And now
my former therapist
is making unannounced house calls
to ensure that I am not a danger .
So , other than that , I 'm really good .
[ phone ringing ]
Should you get that ?
What ?
[ on phone ] Rose , it 's Madeline .
I 've been trying your mobile all morning .
I 'm very concerned about how we left things yesterday .
- Rose ? Are you there ? - No .
[ Madeline on phone ] Hello ?
- No . - Rose ?
No . No .
[ demonic voice ] Almost time , Rose .
What the fuck are you ?
[ growling ]
Ple - - Please .
[ shrieks ]
No , no .
No . No , no .
[ gasping ]
[ laughs ]
No .
[ roars ]
- [ patient laughing ] - [ staff chattering ]
Hey , Dr. Cotter .
Aren 't you supposed to be on leave ?
Just grabbing something from my office .
[ whispering ]
Carl . Hi .
- No . No . - It 's okay .
No , no , no .
- It 's okay . - Oh , God .
No , no . Oh , no , no , no .
- Shh . Shh . Just calm down . - No ! No , no !
- No ! No ! - Shh ! Shut the fuck up .
[ screams ]
Just calm down , okay ? Okay .
- [ Dr. Desai ] Rose . - [ gasps ]
What are you doing here ?
[ Carl babbling ]
I don 't know .
Rose , you can 't be around patients .
[ groans ]
[ shouts ]
[ shouting ]
[ both shouting ]
[ Dr. Desai shouts ]
Fuck ! Rose !
[ screaming ]
[ screams ]
[ breathes heavily ]
Fuck !
[ gasping ]
- [ knocks on window ] - [ horn honks ]
Rose , what are you doing here ?
Nothing .
I don 't - - I don 't know .
I don 't know why . I , uh - -
Why don 't we go inside together and we can just talk ?
No ! It 's - -
It 's not safe .
Rose , I don 't think you should be alone right now .
I need - - I need to be alone .
I need to be - - I need to be alone .
[ stammers ]
I 'm sorry . I 'm sorry . I have to go .
Rose , I don 't think you should go anywhere , okay ?
You just relax , I 'm gonna make a phone call , all right ?
[ screams ]
Rose . Rose , don 't go anywhere .
Wait . Rose , please .
Please don 't go anywhere , okay ? Just hang - -
Rose . Rose , wait ! Rose !
[ gasping ]
[ ringing ]
Joel .
[ Joel ] Rose , I saw a police APB go out for you
that says you 're dangerous . What the fuck happened ?
- I know what I need to do . - What ?
This thing , it needs all of its victims
to pass it on in order to survive ,
but if there 's no one else around , it has no way to pass .
As long as I 'm alone ,
I can deprive it of what it needs .
That doesn 't make any sense .
Your plan is just to avoid people forever ?
I am not gonna keep running , okay ?
I 've got to face it .
Okay , Rose , I 'm coming to you . Just tell me where - -
[ line disconnects ]
[ cell phone ringing ]
[ keys jangle ]
[ lock clicks ]
[ hinge creaking ]
[ light switch clicking ]
[ faint groaning ]
[ groaning continues ]
[ wailing ]
[ groaning , wailing stops ]
[ raspy breathing ]
Rose .
Baby ...
[ crying ]
Help me , please .
Mommy made a mistake .
Get the phone .
Call for help .
[ labored breathing ]
Rose !
[ hinge creaking ]
[ panting ]
- [ door opens ] - [ hinges creaking ]
[ mother sobbing ]
[ sobbing continues ]
[ hinges creaking ]
[ sniffles ]
[ crying ]
Rose . [ gasps ]
It 's okay , baby .
Come here .
I am so sorry .
I - - I haven 't been a good mom .
I want to be . I really try to be .
But sometimes everything is just too much .
There is something terrible inside of me .
- I hate myself . - Stop . Stop . Stop .
Are you ashamed of me ?
No .
Then why did you let me die ?
- Why didn 't you save me ? - It 's not my fault .
- You could have called for help . - Stop . Stop it .
- But you didn 't . - Stop it .
- You wished that I would die . - Because I was afraid of you !
I was ten years old
and you were a monster .
And I know that it 's not fair . You - - You needed help .
But I couldn 't .
And I have carried that guilt
for my entire life .
And I - - I have to let it go .
I ha - - I have to let it go .
This is not real .
But Rose ,
your mind makes it real .
What are you ?
Why are you doing this to me ?
Because your mind ...
[ voice distorting ] ... is so inviting .
[ gasps ]
[ creaking ]
[ chuckling ]
[ gasps ]
[ chuckling continues ]
[ chuckling ]
[ whimpers ]
[ entity screams ]
[ distant laughter echoing ]
[ whimpers ]
[ Rose screams ]
You can 't escape your mind , Rose .
- [ entity chuckles ] - [ Rose coughing ]
[ growls ]
[ gasping , choking ]
It 's - -
- It 's my mind . - [ entity growls ]
- [ grunts ] - [ screams ]
You can 't escape it either .
[ grunts ]
[ roaring ]
[ screaming ]
Rose !
[ growling , screeching ]
[ growling , screeching continues ]
[ coughs ]
[ Joel ] Holy shit .
Are you okay ?
- Can I just come in for a sec ? - Yeah . Yeah , yeah .
Where have you been ?
I 'm sorry .
I 'm sorry for dragging you into my whole fucked-up mess .
[ scoffs ]
For most of my life ,
I 've been afraid of letting people get too close ,
because I was afraid of ...
what they might see if they really looked .
And so I - - I put walls up , and I kept people at a distance .
[ sighs ]
And then ...
I met you ,
and I could feel those walls coming down .
And it scared the shit out of me .
And so ...
I was selfish , and that was not fair to you .
And I am so , so sorry .
And I 'm - - I 'm being selfish again by even asking ,
but do you think that - -
That I could stay here and just ...
just sleep ?
Could you ...
stay with me while I sleep ?
Please .
Yeah , of course I 'll stay with you .
I 'll stay with you forever .
No .
[ chuckling ]
No , no , no , no .
No , no .
[ chuckling continues ]
[ gasps ]
No .
[ screams ]
[ sobs ]
- [ door closes ] - [ Joel ] Rose .
No , no , no !
[ banging ]
- [ Joel ] Rose ! - No .
Rose , open the door !
- Open the door . - [ banging continues ]
Rose !
[ hissing ]
[ thudding , creaking ]
[ chuckling ]
No !
- No ! - Fuck . Uh - -
Hold on . I 'm coming !
No !
[ Rose screaming ]
[ Joel ] Rose !
- [ Rose ] No ! - [ chuckling ]
[ roaring ]
[ screams ]
[ gasps ]
[ entity gasping , distorted ]
[ growling ]
Rose .
[ dripping ]
Rose ?
[ can clatters ]
[ growling , distorted laughter ]
[ flames roaring ]
[ " Lollipop " playing ]
[ song ends ]